Hi, everyone.
I'm here to talk about basically what in
everyday life, what-- how you use agents
and everything, and how it affects the
supply chain around the AI security.
Yeah.
And one thing we have seen pretty common
is, like everyone uses the AI agent.
Even you don't have to be a developer
to use a AI coding agent or even
like build something, right?
Yeah.
Sometimes you just chat with
them, yeah, to understand your
needs and yeah, basically anything
you want to gain knowledge on.
And I think it's not just limited
to adults now, even kids are
using it to do their homeworks.
So I think it's an interesting piece how
it's gonna affect our ecosystem, how our
security of our ecosystem, not just from a
company perspective, but from an end user
perspective, what we are gonna see, right?
Yeah.
So yeah, just let's do
a quick show of hands.
Figure out how many of you
actually use AI coding agents?
Yeah.
Cool.
So I think good number on that, right?
Yeah.
Any one of you use more than one?
Cool.
Yeah.
And have you used Skills?
Okay.
Pretty much, yeah.
And have you ever written any
claude.md or agents.md or any such
instruction file for any other agent?
Yeah.
Great.
Now that I have a good understanding
of basically everyone uses it
you would have used something
like a prompt or anything, yeah.
So this is a Claude prompt, yeah.
Here I say, "Okay, fix this failing test
case." Yeah, very simple Claude prompt.
Yeah.
And I'm on a repository.
I instruct it.
It goes through some things.
Okay, do you want to proceed, right?
Yeah.
And what do you select?
Yes, and always allow access or No?
Yeah.
One of these.
And pretty sure you'll
be choosing option two.
Yeah.
Because you don't want to be bothered.
And that is why humans are one
of the biggest weakest link
because they get tired, right?
Yeah.
They get tired of those recursive
prompts that keep coming.
Yeah.
We don't want this.
Sometimes I myself, I am a head
of research, and I still run it
with the most insecure format.
Yeah.
It's like that.
We are the humans, we are the weakest
link, and that's an acceptance
that we will have to deal with.
There's no other way.
And of course, it goes
through many stages, right?
So when you wrote that prompt, of
course it first reads your claude.md.
Yeah.
In-- Basically enforces
your requirement, right?
What you have said.
Yeah.
Connects if you have some
MCV servers, et cetera.
Tries to see, okay, how can I solve this?
Connects all that data.
Yeah.
Pulls all the linked issues, PRs, and
everything, and retrieves the knowledge
from your code on what the issue is about.
Yeah.
Loads your environment variables, tokens,
delegated credentials, all of this.
Of course, not in this order.
Yeah.
But it does all of this.
Then is the environment provisioning.
It tries to, let's say,
run the test, right?
Because you said, "Okay, fix the
PR." So it tries to run the test.
Finds, okay setups missing.
Looks like a freshly cloned repo, right?
Yeah, could be that.
Let's say it's a Python repo.
Creates a virtual environment, right?
Based on if you have a .python file
there or if you don't have anything,
it will just try to assume something
what's locally available, create that.
Yeah.
Resolve the dependencies
and versions, install that.
Yeah.
And reruns the test.
Reads the logs reasons over the failures.
Yeah.
Edits the source and any of the
configs that it will have, right?
Installs.
Okay, figures out, okay, to run this
test, I have added a new dependency.
Let me install it.
Yeah.
Reruns until green.
And then propagates, stage the
commit writes a commit message
and everything, pushes it to a
remote front based on how you have
instructed in the claude.md, right?
Yeah.
And that's how the entire
kind of workflow happens.
Yeah.
Now, one thing is basically we--
this was a good prompt, right?
Yeah.
We just said, "Fix this PR." Yeah.
But it doesn't take much to change
from a good prompt to a bad prompt.
Yeah.
It's just one missing step,
one missing, one inclusion from
somewhere that you don't want to.
Yeah.
And a good prompt, a perfectly benign
prompt turns into a malicious one.
Yeah.
Now what's the blast radius, right?
Look at how many things
we give access to, right?
Yeah.
We are not running AI agents,
in a remote SSH environment.
We are running it on our workstations
where we have access to everything.
Yeah.
No matter how good the guardrails
are added on top of it, there is
always something that's flawed,
and we have discovered it.
Every month, there is
a flaw in that piece.
Yeah.
And your file system secrets,
connection to public internet, right?
Your package registries that you have,
the identity systems or an-anything that
you are-- that is issuing, for example,
even AWS credentials, et cetera, all
those pieces, and your downstream CI.
So you have-- You're trying to
simplify your life by giving
it more and more connectivity.
Yeah.
But that is also the blast radius as well.
And this was previously, right?
Yeah.
You-- All of you would have
remembered how you would code before
or look at things before, right?
Yeah.
You have a source code, package manager,
build pipeline, artifact deploy.
Yeah.
No more boring stuff, right?
It's all agentic.
Let's include agents everywhere.
That's the new kind of the new
delivery of the new era, and
Harness believes in that as well.
Yeah.
So we are building
agents across everything.
Yeah.
Which means, okay, AI agents, not
just, write the codes and the pipeline.
We also install dependencies,
reviews the PR, right?
Yeah.
One thing is left is, okay, for
the humans, okay, as a gate, right?
Yeah, approve the PR.
Yeah.
I don't know, maybe six months,
a year down the line, we
might see agents approving PR.
Yeah.
We are not sure.
There are-- By the way, there are
already agents that are approving
PRs in open source repository.
If you'll see if all checks
pass, everything's good, yeah,
pre-approve it based on those gates.
Yeah.
And agents fix and run those pipelines
if there are any bugs, right?
Yeah.
Merge codes, artifacts, deploy.
Not just deploy, monitor how
the production is behaving
with this new deployment.
Yeah.
And then do some patches, rollbacks.
That's what Harness does.
Yeah.
I'm proud to say all of this.
But it all brings us all
of this multiple attacks.
Yeah.
And let's see what happened in the past.
Some of the supply chain
attacks that were in the news.
Yeah.
Of course, if I start listing, maybe we
all will be here until maybe even a week.
Yeah.
That's how many supply chain
attacks have happened in the past.
Yeah.
So this was one of the most newsworthy
one, was the SolarWinds before AI agents.
Yeah.
They infiltrated kind of the build
pipeline and basically slipped the
backdoor into the monitoring software and
shipped a perfectly signed package, right?
And every customer this included
almost four hundred plus of the
Fortune five hundreds all five
divisions of US government.
Yeah.
So you can think the amount
of impact this brought, right?
Yeah.
And it took nine months
to identify this backdoor.
Yeah.
That was one, yeah.
CodeCov not so far in the memory, yeah.
E-I, even I experienced
parts of this, yeah.
Of course, not much impact, yeah.
But we did see some parts of this
open repositories where we used to use
CodeCov the this vulnerability, yeah.
And it basically hijacked the batch
uploader where it ran a script and
exfiltrated environment variables,
et cetera, which could be later
utilized in other pieces of attacks.
Now, this became one of the
biggest bases of attacks that
came later in, in these stages.
Yeah.
So this was something
that was very different.
Yeah.
Here, basically, Alex Birsan, who
actually, you know… basically when you
use artifact registries or anything in
your development you would see, okay,
your artifact registries goes ahead,
pulls a package from your artifacts,
then it goes and pulls it from, public
registries because you specify could be
if you use Java, Maven even your internal
registries, JFrog if you have one, right?
Yeah.
So you'll specify all of
those different pieces.
Yeah.
And there's one thing that
plays a big role, is preference.
Yeah.
And here's what was wrong.
It didn't matter the preference of
where registry you're pulling from, it
matters which vers-version is higher.
Yeah.
If I have 4.0 in the public
registry, ignore the 3, 3.0.
If someone says latest, pull
4.0 from the public registry.
Yeah.
And that's what Alex Birsan did.
He created packages with names that
internal repositories would have with
malicious intention externally, and
thirty-five plus organizations almost.
He got one thirty K plus bounties.
But I think this is what
publicly was there, and there
was no exploit as such here.
It was basically, he just was testing
this, but this was the impact.
Yeah.
So a good guy in that way.
Now ExitUtils.
This was basically one of the historical
attacks where kind of the entirely
fake persona existed to develop a
trust in an open source community.
Yeah.
He came and built a trust
over years, two years, right?
Yeah.
And inserted a backdoor into the
build process hidden in inside a test
file, which actually hijacked the
SSH connection, yeah, and would have
granted access to a lot of people.
Yeah.
Now, how was this caught?
A very simple thing.
Yeah.
A developer was irritated by five hundred
millisecond delay in SSH connections.
Yeah.
And he started inspecting it
and identified that piece.
Yeah.
So- Look at it there's also efforts
that people go to certain extent, yeah.
If it was an AI agent, it wouldn't bother
with five hundred milliseconds, right?
Yeah.
It was a developer, so he noticed it.
LiteLLM, very recent one.
Yeah.
And here we saw basically the Trivy
actions or actually which w- which
was actually compromised before.
Yeah.
They utilized the same security
scanner, which was supposed to
secure the LiteLLM artifacts and
repositories into compromising and
publishing a vulnerable hook file.
Actually, it's called PTH in Python.
Yeah.
So .PTH files are something that
anytime you start a interpreter,
anytime you say Python, yeah, it
will load all the PTH files for
basically your works- workspace, right?
Yeah.
And tries to set it up, make it ready for
your environment, which means you don't
have to do anything to get exploited.
Just type Python, which is
commonly everyone does it.
Yeah.
And yeah, again, official hack.
Then came ShyULul.
I think most people would have heard
this because it made a lot of noise.
Yeah.
Almost the entire npm stack of
around TAN Stack and many other
libraries actually got compromised.
Yeah.
There were two waves, September
twenty to five, then again November
twenty-five, but it didn't stop there.
It again used the same har-
credential harvesting techniques.
Yeah.
But this time utilized TruffleHog
to actually search for the secrets.
TruffleHog is basically a secret scanner.
Yeah.
And it was nice to see actors
or basically bad actors actually
utilizing a security scanner to
identify, "Okay, where are the secrets?
Let me identify those." Yeah.
So we do it for the purpose of we
don't leak it, they do it for the
purpose of, "Okay, let's leak it." Yeah
And one of the last ones
that we're talking about.
Yeah.
It was Mimasa Mini Mias- Miasma
or basically Mini Shyuloth.
Yeah.
So basically, this was a bit targeted in a
similar manner of Shyuloth, but the change
was basically they utilized, of course,
a bad bash expl-- exporter or an uploader
file script to upload these credentials.
But there were few things that stood
out in this attack was AI involvement.
Yeah.
This was powered by AI.
Basically, it could recraft and
create payloads, embed those
into your coding tools, agents,
et cetera, and all those pieces.
Now, another piece of bypass they
used, interestingly, was, they added,
prompt to build a nuclear bomb yeah.
And for example, if if you go and type how
to build a nuclear bomb in Anthropic or
any of this Claude or a-any Google SDK or
Gemini, e-even a kind of ChatGPT, y-you'll
see one thing, they will refuse, right?
Yeah.
Because that's the guardrail,
which means all people who had
built AI inspections to identify
malwares, this could bypass those.
Yeah.
And that was the intention.
So as we build softwares, attackers
are evolving at double the speed before
even we think in those directions.
Yeah.
And we have to get hundred
percent of the things right, they
just have to get one percent.
Yeah
So one thing we learned from this
is anytime, if you see all of these
attacks, one thing was common.
First time there was, the trusted update
that was compromised, then a tool, yeah.
Then the package manager, then
the contributor, yeah, and
the release channel, yeah.
All of this where we trust, right?
Yeah.
The maintainers, yeah
Basically, one thing is
common is attackers are
following where the trust is.
Yeah.
Why try to, exhaust ourself into
try to find a vulnerability?
Yeah.
Go where the trust is and you exploit
a massive user base and space.
Yeah.
So that's what they're l- looking into.
And trust is moving
towards the agent, right?
You trust all the answers that
ChatGPT gives most of the time.
Yeah.
I don't know, how many times
do you verify basically what
it said, what code it wrote?
Do you go line by line?
No.
I don't think so.
Yeah.
So it's pretty common.
And that trust is what's being exploited.
Yeah.
And many things that we see in
terms of trust exploitation is
they, embed a large chunk of script.
They embed, hidden Unicode characters.
Yeah.
That's not visible to human
naked eye, but visible to agents.
They embed special characters, yeah,
to stop evaluations from happening
so that if s- it sees a binary,
maybe it will stop inspection the
payload because it's a security
scanner, it will not inspect binaries.
It's only searching on the code, right?
Yeah.
So there are a lot of things that
we are seeing on that perspective.
Yeah.
And of course, AI coding
assistants are no longer option.
Yeah.
Almost eighty percent adoption
rate in the world that has already
been proved few months back,
maybe ninety percent right now.
Yeah.
And code volume and even the
security, I think experience.
Almost we can see every application
that is built by agent has
some form of vulnerability.
Yeah
Now, if you look at the coding
a-agent and the ecosystem, right?
Yeah.
We have basically agent instructions,
configs, code, hooks, skills, right?
Tools, slash commands that you have, yeah,
MCP servers, yeah, new things workflows,
yeah, and of course agents and sub-agents
that we have always seen, so there's a
lot of, area and this evolution is like
within last one year if you see, right?
Yeah.
Security vendors or even people
like have not gotten even a
chance to think what can we do?
How to secure them?
How to implement them?
And it's also a race between,
the AI vendors themselves.
Yeah.
They are trying to push,
how can I be the top?
Yeah.
It's not about, how can
I solve one problem?
No one agrees to be a second one.
Yeah.
Everyone is racing for the top race.
Yeah
And with all this, of course, now
if I'm talking about supply chain, I
first need to in-introspect myself.
So what I did was I built kind
of a script, yeah, a tool in
en-entirety, a discovery tool
which I can, run on my system.
Identify, let's see what's on
my system on all these pieces.
Yeah.
So I found eleven hundred and
three artifacts, out of which
fifty percent I was not aware of.
Yeah.
Some enabled by our IT teams, yeah,
which they have been pushing through
secret channels to see what's being
installed, what's being worked on.
Some, by external tools, et
cetera, that I'm installing.
Yeah.
Some, of course, based on repositories,
markdowns by our colleagues.
Yeah.
And of course, all of this, one thing I
saw is one fifty-eight skills that I had.
Maybe I had done ten, ten of them,
but more than that I didn't-- I
expected it would be th- there
would be a good count, but I didn't
expect I would have one fifty-eight
skills in my laptop being present.
Yeah.
There were eight-thirty markdown
rules like Claude.md, Agents.md
across all the repository.
Because I am a security researcher, I
work across huge chunks of repositories.
Yeah.
So of course, this was still
expected as a high number, but not
eight hundred and thirty, right?
Yeah.
We saw MCP servers, yeah.
Registered commands,
of course this was me.
Yeah.
And hooks, something of
course, for the introspection.
Anytime, for example, if any IT company
wants to embed themselves, into the
developer process, let's see whom they
are sending, what they are sending.
So this is where they inject the process.
So hooks are a place which is being
utilized for security in your AI coding
agents, in your basically in your
day-to-day interaction or activities.
And any agent you build also
using an agentic framework.
For example, if you're building
a multi-agent system, you will
see if you need open telemetry
access or any of those pieces.
For example, many of the talk-- talked
about multi-agent system, open telemetry.
You'll require those hooks.
Yeah.
Different forms, of course,
different implementations, but
in the end, those are hooks.
How do you inject yourself into
the agent reasoning, thinking, and
extract that knowledge at that piece?
Yeah.
And then of course, many agents
also started supporting workflows.
Four of them, which I
had used for testing.
And of course I also did, okay, how
many AI coding agent traces do I have?
Of course, I right now use only
four, but there were five, one of
them which I stopped using before.
Yeah.
So let's peel back on
some of the layers, right?
Yeah.
The mechanics of the agentic risk.
For life we have seen basically how
do we define agents and where do
we define all those pieces, right?
Yeah.
We have claude.md, agents.md.
There is prompt.md for few.
Yeah.
.cursor rules, windsurf rules,
mcp.json, settings.json.
Yeah.
And this is across different areas.
So there will be a local config, there
will be a global, glo-global config.
Yeah.
So resolution and all that piece.
And then there is also how you do this.
And now what's the recommendation?
Let's take all of this, commit it so
that other users can also use it, right?
Yeah.
And how many of you have ever reviewed
when you clone a PR or anything what's
e-existing in a claude.md or agents.md?
Yeah.
Okay.
Great, yeah.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
It's lovely to see.
So if you see one thing, we we
have an inheritance trust from
the ecosystem as well, right?
Yeah.
Our colleagues have pushed it.
It's safe for sure, right?
Yeah.
But we don't know where
they copied it from.
Yeah.
Might be generated by ChatGPT or
might be, a good skill someone said on
the internet that does all the work.
Yeah.
Let's just take it and paste it in the
workflow, and i- when I type a prompt,
all my code will be, elite developer code.
Yeah.
So it could be that as well.
So we don't know.
Yeah
And one thing we have
learned the hard way, right?
Yeah.
Not to commit dot ENV files, but
now we commit an entire behavior.
We commit how agent should work.
Yeah.
There are YAML builders for agent.
So we commit how the agent should behave.
Everything needs to be committed, right?
Yeah.
But it also brings those
commits we also utilize.
Yeah.
Which means when we fork those
code, when we, start working on
something new or on a repository
that we have not worked on, yeah.
Every time we are carrying an
inherent risk of everything
that has happened with it.
Yeah, all those commits.
And hooks.
It's basically ev-every
time we have seen something.
Previously, malwares used to use
dot bash RC, dot JSCH RC, or any
RC file, to embed themselves.
Hooks have become the dot bash RC
problem for the agents at scale.
Yeah.
Good for enforcing tools, right?
Blocking dangerous operations
and auditing everything.
Yeah.
The same thing, run code on
every prompt, every action.
For example, there are,
like, almost twenty types of
hooks I remember from Claude.
Yeah.
And it could be embedded in
any of those pieces, right?
Yeah.
Silently modifies context.
Few of our research pieces
actually showed us we could bypass
all the systems using hooks.
Yeah.
Because hooks could edit other hooks.
Nicely, no alerts, no queries,
okay, allow, no allow.
Doesn't matter.
Yeah.
It will happen.
Exfiltrate tool calls and arguments, yeah.
Of course, yeah.
Sometimes it didn't even require much.
Yeah.
We could, integrate a malicious
piece into an MCP server.
A, a malicious prompt in an
MCP server, yeah, which someone
uses, will embed a hook that
will do all the malicious things.
Yeah.
So one thing agents are
the decision-makers that
we have in the system.
Yeah.
So let's take another scenario, right?
Let's say today we write a simple
sentence into the agent memory.
Okay, use mock payment tool for,
test-testing the payment authorization.
Yeah.
Now, we have said it to the
agent, we have forgotten about
it because our memory is short.
Yeah.
We do so many of those things
every day, we don't remember
the small nitty-gritties.
Yeah.
Of course, this memory kind of keeps in
the back, back, back burner of the system.
Yeah.
The vector database doesn't
know where to fetch it from.
Yeah.
It's not about recency for
them, it's about relevance.
And any times there will be mock and
payment, yeah, it will pull all of this.
Yeah.
I've, of course, shortened this
prompt, but it might be a very long
prompt that we would provide, right?
Yeah.
It will only bring that relevant
part of the context, and weeks,
days, or months later, yeah, it
authorizes, an unauthorized payment.
Yeah.
Because okay, it remembers,
okay, let's use the mock one.
Yeah.
So it says, "Okay, mock payment
authorizes it. Let's do transfer." Yeah.
So kind of knowledge and decisions,
the risk that we are transferring
with it, yeah, it has to be granularly
audited not in terms of just the
prompts or the data that we have.
It's also now the agent memory in itself.
Yeah.
We are building a system
like, that we can't see.
Yeah.
So th-that is a problem.
We can't see agent layers and memories.
For example, when you are
saying, "Okay, fix this PR," we
didn't tell it, how to do it.
We didn't tell it wh-where
to find everything.
Yeah.
It did everything based on previous
context, and if we had a previous session
there, it would avoid many of those
steps because it had already done the
embeddings and memory stores locally.
So if you ever want to check out
what your agents have saved, you can
actually see they build databases.
You go to .Claude folder or .Cursor
folder, you'll be able to see all those
pieces that are being developed there.
Yeah.
Now, let's say we have a
million documents, right?
Yeah.
How many malicious ones will we
need to hijack a specific answer?
in a million documents
How much?
Okay.
Yeah.
A bit lower?
Huh?
One?
Okay.
Yeah, quite close.
Yeah.
It's five documents in a million.
So this is proven.
It leads to ninety percent success rate.
Yeah.
And this is the same problem.
We have to be very careful with all
of the pieces that we develop as well.
For example, if you are building,
agent guardrails if you are training
models, yeah, which means just
five of those malicious ones will
affect our entire agent's memory
with ninety percent success rate.
So your data is a key element
into how your agents behave now.
Yeah
Another problem, of course,
let's look at the third angle.
Yeah.
Before, agents, we had typos
spotting, humans type request
with, okay any missing, right?
Yeah.
So that was called typos spotting.
Humans misspell things.
Yeah.
Agents don't misspell things.
They are very good at, spellings, yeah,
because they have learned the world
vocabulary, yeah, and trained on, I
think, trillions of parameters, right?
Yeah.
So they do really good job at it.
But they hallucinate.
They, can make up packages
that never existed before.
Yeah.
So if you say, "Okay, build me a, a secure
way to write this JSON parser." Okay.
It'll say, "Okay, import
secure adjacent." Yeah.
Or, "Secure JSON." Yeah.
The packet never existed.
Yeah.
It just invented it.
Now, all an attacker needs to do
is register this package and foof.
Yeah.
So AI, this is a place where AI,
is the victim, is the weapon.
Yeah.
And a victim designing
a weapon for itself.
Yeah
And of course these were, things
that we have not seen before.
Few things that I observed
with myself as well.
Yeah.
One of them was Claude didn't hesitate,
for example, in committing credentials
or .env files or anything as such.
Yeah.
Of course, it wouldn't read it, but it
was perfectly fine in committing it.
Yeah.
It didn't hesitate.
I said, "Okay, let's commit
all the files." Yeah.
It took including the .env
file and committed it.
Yeah.
And of course, that was one part of it.
Then there is cross-tool blindness.
What it means is, let's say I I
think many of you people raised
for multiple tools usage, right?
Yeah.
For example, Claude, if I try to do
something malicious with it, okay go
ahead and change your hook or change
your setting files, it wouldn't do it.
Yeah.
But if I decide for Cursor or Windsurf,
it would go and deliberately change it.
So being aware of its own
self, it had some guardrails.
It had… And actually, those
guardrails are stored in a config
that, okay, these files are secure.
Files, do not touch them, yeah, without
approvals or deny changing them.
Yeah.
But it hasn't encompassed about all the
other AI ecosystem, and it's evolving.
Yeah.
So it deliberately goes ahead and change
those because it's no intelligence.
Yeah.
It's basically the reasoning that
it does, yeah, and it writes.
It's AI agents are nothing
but an autocomplete agent.
Yeah.
They are not thinking when they are
saying, "Okay, we are reasoning." Yeah.
They are just autocompleting and
then running neural algorithms,
select the best answer.
Yeah.
And then from that, keep on
going for the best answer.
Yeah.
So that reinforcement feed
is what gives us the answer.
It's not thinking, in terms
of what's good, what's bad.
It doesn't have an intuition.
Yeah.
It has what it can teach, learn
from the dataset and act on.
Yeah So of course we talked
about all the problems.
Now, what do we need, right?
Yeah.
Kill switch, for sure.
Anytime we see any of these problems,
one thing is always an emergency brake.
How do I stop what's happening?
Yeah.
Now, the hooks are, exploitable themself.
So if you use hooks for killing it,
might be they themselves get killed.
Yeah.
So we have to come up with ways
by which we can safeguard it.
And of course, it's up-- it's the
responsibility of AI vendors to
provide an extensive mechanism that
cannot be manipulated, that can be
utilized, by security tools, et cetera.
Yeah.
And circuit breakers and agent
system suspensions, almost similar
things, but it has to be coming
from the vendors themselves.
Yeah.
These are not something
that we can design.
Of course, we can utilize the
hooks, to safeguard against,
okay, this prompt looks unsafe.
This prompt is ex-exfilling
sensitive data.
Yeah.
Okay the security tool inspected, AI
firewall inspected it, blocked it.
Yeah.
But if there is going to be
such scale of malware attacks,
and we are seeing it every day.
Last night again, we had one.
Yeah.
And th-there's no way of stopping them.
They are automating it at the
lengths that, the entire industry
is not able to catch up with.
Yeah.
Same.
One thing we have seen is what do we add?
Most of the time to use a
Claude.md, use an API key.
Yeah.
Or use a for Bedrock for a-anyone using
Bedrock, also people use access keys.
Yeah.
But there are better ways.
Roles, right?
Yeah.
Or small granted roles
that you can provide.
Yeah.
You can use identity badges.
So basically, when you use roles and
when you use this for example, we
ourself use roles in terms of Bedrock.
Yeah.
We-- What security grants is I can
have, let's say, a session that expires
every twenty-four hours, but with
that is anytime, let's say, someone
steals my credentials, it's gonna
be only valid for twenty-four hours.
Yeah.
And it becomes kind of a
safety net, a defense in depth.
Yeah.
So agents need those employee
badges, yeah, that we can be
audited, that can be revoked, right?
Yeah.
And that's becoming an
important piece of information.
Yeah.
Static API keys, of course, is
the same anti-pattern that were
for passwords for sticky notes.
Yeah.
This is same for agents.
Of course the models itself, right?
Yeah.
Anytime when we use models especially
if you're using custom models.
Yeah.
One thing is verification layers they
are not so matured right now, of course.
So we need to mature as an organization,
as a user itself on seeing basically
how we can use trusted models.
We need to demand for trusted models.
We need to demand for, signature
verification and security.
Only then all the publishers of
models will come up and provide us
with a trusted signature mechanism.
Of course the regulators and everyone
have moved in this direction,
but not everyone is providing
us with secure trusted models.
Yeah
And of course auditing the
agent permissions and trust.
Yeah.
So anytime if you get time for sure,
go ahead look at a laptop, look at,
what does your .Cursor folder contain.
Look at what your .Claude folder contain.
Yeah, look at what even your
repositories that you'll be
using with other people contain.
Because those dot files, most of the
time they are hidden from our eyes.
Yeah.
We don't look at them.
Always inspect once in a while.
Look at those.
Yeah.
What's there?
If I was surprised, I'm
sure you will be too.
Yeah.
And of course, treat all
of them as source code.
Yeah.
Any of this, you know, configurations
that we are building for agents, we
need to treat them as source code.
We need to review what's going on
because these are directions that we are
providing for agents, and we need to be
hundred percent sure what we are saying
it to them, not copy-pasting, someone--
somewhere from a, a skill from internet
because someone said, "Good." Yeah.
And of course, it's not just that people
have enabled, marketplace for skills.
You just have to type a URL and
all the skills are there with you.
Yeah.
So that's much dangerous aspect
of skills and invocations.
Yeah.
And of course, we are building
kind of evaluators for skills,
evaluators for configs.
Yeah.
I'm looking at how we can make
all of these pieces secure soon.
Yeah.
Now, most of the time, basically
when we use models of course, I'm
not talking about Claude and Cursor
because they are spending four
hundred millions testing those models.
Yeah.
But still they are vulnerable.
So think about people who
are building, models that are
publishing at Hugging Face.
Yeah.
Smaller models things, that are fine-tuned
specifically for s-smaller purposes.
Yeah.
I don't think they are investing
that much time into, red teaming.
And even if there's tomorrow
a security benchmark that
can say this model is secure
Models in a way basically all AI
agents can be made in a way that
they can bypass the models themself
or the benchmarks themself, right?
Yeah.
So the problem with inherent risk
is there are lots of pieces, lots
of moving pieces in AI agent, and I
think it will take few years for us to
evolve as a ma-mature ecosystem of AI.
Yeah.
Till then, I think every one of
us have a onus to make ourself
and our ecosystem secure.
Yeah.
AI red teaming becomes a key piece in
itself, yeah, because if you're not
evaluating how your model behaves in
different scenarios and syntax, yeah, I
think you will find that somewhere down
the line it punishes you And of course,
NIST AI six hundred and one, which
is the specification for agentic AI.
Yeah.
It clearly incorporates red
teaming as a critical component to
measure to its measure function.
Yeah.
Now, of course, few things that
have evolved from the regulatory
and industry perspective.
Yeah, CycloneDX produced the ML BOM,
but thenSPDX also provided an AI
BOM, yeah, which kind of provides
us with a verification layer.
So if you have worked in governance
and this aspect, you will see
provenance, SLSA and provenance.
This is coming to agentic models now,
which is a good thing because which
means just our inherent packages that we
use to install, we will also see… For
example, if you use Ollama or anything
we'll see that it's also looking at
and matching the hashes that there
is no tampering with those models.
It's a verified model piece.
Yeah.
Of course, it will always live the r-
let the risk live in our hands with an
insecure flag that we can always add.
Yeah.
But at least things are
maturing in those pieces.
Yeah.
And for example, regulators themselves
EU AI Act brought a very strong binding
structure that you have to follow a rating
mechanism, of course, for your model.
How risky is your model?
Rate it between A, B, C, D, E, like yeah.
And it's giving it a tier
that, okay, my model's risky.
You have to tell it, not the
customers have to find it out.
You have to tell how you're utilizing
AI, how you're utilizing sensitive data
across them, and you have to tell about it
basically how risky your model is so that
controls can be applied according to that.
Yeah.
And these are some good
things that are coming out.
Of course, NIST also brought,
but it's still voluntary.
We will see some of the maturity
aspects of it as it comes, and
ISO also brings parts of it.
But still there are lots of unsolved
gaps that we have seen, right?
Yeah.
For example, MCP servers, yeah.
They never, We-- have you ever
seen a signed MCP server, right?
Yeah.
A cert-validated MCP server.
MCP servers, I think they are
inherently in a way that, okay of
course you have stdio-based, basically
local development-based, right?
Yeah.
But you also have SSE or streaming-based
MCP servers, which you can in include from
local or even from remote perspective.
Yeah.
Like a GitHub MCP server, et cetera.
Those pieces.
There are lots of pieces that
are still unsolved for because it
has evolved in such a short time.
We haven't seen solutions to this.
Yeah.
And I think these are things that we need.
For example, even hooks that are getting
installed, there is no verification layer.
I cannot know where did it come from.
Yeah.
Because I recognize my IT team, I know,
okay, they have done this malicious thing
in my system, monitoring all my prompts.
Yeah.
But- Tomorrow, if I see that especially
with so many tools and so many
monitoring aspects coming in, I'll
see, another sort of hook in that.
Yeah.
Today it's, let's say
ten, I can monitor it.
Tomorrow when it's gonna be fifty
of those, yeah, I will never
even bother looking at that.
So that aspects are coming, which means
we need a trust verification layer for
all this and attribution, of course.
Who's publishing this?
Where is it coming from?
We need all of this
defined in those pieces.
Yeah.
And of course, cross-agent guardrails.
Cursor and Claude, they
need to work as a team, man.
Yeah.
There's no way you can safeguard yourself
but leave your neighbors vulnerable.
Yeah.
So yeah, of course, those pieces
of awareness needs to come from
and it needs to mature from the
a- and provider's perspective.
Yeah.
But the last piece, of course,
is decision monitoring and audit.
Yeah.
Which means it's not just
the onus of, providers or our
organizations, it's also a onus of us.
Of course, we always choose
the option two, you remember?
Yeah.
But it's the onus of us once in
a while to look through all those
pieces that we click yes through.
Yeah.
So yeah, a small cheat sheet
on where we see every aspect.
Yeah.
And this is, of course, just a small list.
There's so much to do in this area
that I can clearly say AI supply
chain is completely broken right now.
Yeah.
There is no way to even fifty percent
secure it in that perspective.
It's such an evolving journey,
and we have to come up together
across all these pieces to build
an AI supply chain mechanism.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Any questions anyone has?
Yes, chief.
Okay
And it's the signal that happens
Sorry?
The signal that, yeah
Yes.
Yeah.
Of course model are
intent-based behaviors, right?
So it's not just the models itself.
Basically, the firewalls itself are
evolving on that aspect, that they're
measuring the intent of your thought.
For example, one of the simple thing was,
send a, a picture of, cat and, a file.
Yeah.
And then it will, the
model will, cat the file.
Or it-- send a picture of dustbin and
a file name in the picture itself,
it'll go ahead and delete that file.
Yeah.
So we have seen that
happen with even Claude.
Yeah.
So we have seen intent taking action,
even though there was no meaning of
that from an English perspective,
but the agent understood it from the
perspective of, what an image means,
yeah reasoned over it and acted on it.
Yeah.
So of course, the firewalls have to
evolve in that action, and also from
the end-end customer's perspective or
from the end user's perspective, right?
Yeah.
Not everything happen in ten milliseconds.
So everyone expects, that we add
any firewall solution or anything,
we-- it should not add latency.
When your agents are taking two to three
minutes to complete a task, you can
give them a buffer of another hundred
second-- milliseconds, to do the job.
There's no way that ten-millisecond
firewall is gonna work for all
those intent-based use cases.
Yeah.
Anything else, anyone?
Thank you, everyone.
It was nice having you here.
Join me and stay this late
with us on a working day.
Thank you very much.